Papers of the International Labor Defense on Microfilm 5815 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Papers of the International Labor Defense on Microfilm
1842-1951
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Labor Defense
5815 mf
2.44 cubic feet
22 microfilm reels
Records (documents), microfilm.
Part of 'Black Studies Research Sources', General Editors - August Meier and John H. Bracey, Jr.
5710655
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Labor Defense (ILD) was legal advocacy organization established in the United States as the American section of the Comintern's International Red Aid network. The ILD defended Sacco and Vanzetti, was active in the civil rights and anti-lynching movements, and prominently participated in the defense and legal appeals in the cause celebre of the Scottsboro Boys. In 1946 the ILD was merged with National Federation for Constitutional Liberties to form the Civil Rights Congress, which served as the new legal defense organization of the Communist Party USA. [Wikipedia]
Scope and Contents
Part of 'Black Studies Research Sources', General Editors - August Meier and John H. Bracey, Jr.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5156m: Save the Scottsboro Boys Stamps 5276: International Workers Order (IWO) Records 5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5 5780/014: ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Papers 5780/047: ILGWU Joint Board Dress & Waistmakers' Union of Greater New York Managers' Correspondence 5780/178: ILGWU Charles Zimmerman Collection of Radical Pamphlets 5815 mf: Papers of the International Labor Defense on Microfilm 5831 mf: The CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. II: CIO General Files on Microfilm 5863 mf: Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm 5928: Elaine Leeder Collection of Rose Pesotta Papers 6034: Rare Pamphlet Collection 6046: Archives Union File (AUF)
Civil rights--United States--History--Sources.; Discrimination in employment--Law and legislation--United States--History--Sources.; African Americans-- Civil rights--History--Sources.; Bracey, John H.; Meier, August; International Labor Defense.; Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture.
5710655
- 0001. Box 1/Folder a1.Constitution of the International Labor Defense., 1925-1939; 1 (Reel 1)
- 0002. Box 1/Folder a1. Constitution of International Labor Defense (ILD): As Adopted June 22, 1937, and Amended July 9, 1939. 9 pages., 1937-1939; 2 (Reel 1)
- 0011. Box 1/Folder a1. Labor Defense: Manifesto, Resolutions, and Constitution Adopted by the First National Conference. 9 pages., 1925; 3 (Reel 1)
  Scope and Contents
  June 28, 1925
- 0020. Box 1/Folder a2. Minutes and Reports., 1929; 4 (Reel 1)
- 0021. Box 1/Folder a2. Call for the Fourth National Conference of the International Labor Defense to Be Held in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. 2 pages., 1929; 5 (Reel 1)
  December 29-31, 1929
- 0023. Box 1/Folder a2. Report on Cases Handled by International Labor Defense. 30 pages., 1929; 6 (Reel 1)
  Topics Included: Cases resulting from distributing literature and attempting to organize workers; cases resulting from holding meetings and demonstrations; deportation cases; cases resulting from picketing and general strike activity; cases resulting from the National Textile Workers' Union; sedition and criminal syndicalist cases; cases resulting from general capitalist terror campaign; additional cases growing from strike activity; Tom Mooney and Warren Billings cases; Centralia, Washington, cases; miscellaneous cases
- 0053. Box 1/Folder a3. Minutes and Reports., 1937; 7 (Reel 1)
- 0054. Box 1/Folder a3. Program for Round Table Discussions at the National Conference of the International Labor Defense to be Held in Washington, D.C. 4 pages., 1937; 8 (Reel 1)
  June 19-21, 1937. Topics included: Criminal syndicalism and related repressive legislation; protection of the foreign-born and the right of asylum; the present situation in Puerto Rico; prison conditions in the United States and the recognition of the status of political prisoners; the events in Spain today and their significance to the American people; anti-lynching legislation and defense of the rights of the Negro people; the Tom Mooney case; civil rights in America today.
- 0058. Box 1/Folder a3. Draft Resolutions for the International Labor Defense National Conference. 36 pages., 1937; 9 (Reel 1)
  Topics included: Greetings to all prisoners; the Scottsboro, Alabama case; Tom Mooney and Warren Billings; Ernest Thaelmann; the chain gang; against lynching; the Modesto, California case; status of political prisoners; the Sacramento, California case; Senator Robert M. La Follette Committee; Poland; Labor Defender; J.B. McNamara and Matthew Schmidt; criminal syndicalism and other repressive legislation; democratic rights in Puerto Rico; Paul and Gertrude Ruegg; Italy; Brazilian political prisoners; Earl King - Ernest G. Ramsey - Frank J. Connor Case; Sheppard-Hill bill; right of asylum; protection of the foreign-born; the Dies bill; Matthias Rakosi; embargo on arms to Italy and Germany; legislative program; adoption of constitution of International Labor defense; Tampa, Florida, Joseph Shoemaker case; murder of Frank Norman; the Black Legion; Alabama; Arkansas; Cuba.
- 0094. Box 1/Folder a3. Report of National Executive Committee by Anna Damon. 29 pages., 1937; 10 (Reel 1)
- 0123. Box 1/Folder a3. Resolutions of International Labor Defense National Conference. 41 pages., 1937; 11 (Reel 1)
  Topics Included: Resolution on adoption of constitution of International Labor Defense; the South; terror against steel workers; seamen; civil and democratic rights; terror in Hawaii; greetings to all prisoners; Tom Mooney and Warren K. Billings; Ernest Thaelmann; the chain gang; against lynching; the Modesto, California, case; status of political prisoners; the Sacramento, California, case; Senator Robert M. La Follette Committee; Poland; Labor Defender: J.B. McNamara and Matthew Schmidt; criminal syndicalism and other repressive legislation; democratic rights in Puerto Rico; Paul and Gertrude Ruegg; Italy; Brazilian political prisoners; Ernest King-Ernest G. Ramsey-Frank J. Connor case; Sheppard-Hill bill; right of asylum; protection of foreign born; the Dies bill; Matthias Rakosi; embargo on arms to Italy and Germany; legislative program; adoption of constitution of International Labor Defense; Tampa, Florida, Joseph Shoemaker case; murder of Frank Norman; the Black Legion; Alabama; Arkansas.
- 0164. Box 1/Folder a4. Minutes and Reports., 1937; 12 (Reel 1)
- 0165. Box 1/Folder a4. Plans for the Washington International Labor Defense National Conference. 7 pages., 1937; 13 (Reel 1)
  April 24, 1937
- 0172. Box 1/Folder a4. Minutes of the International Labor Defense National Conference. 10 pages., 1937; 14 (Reel 1)
  June 19-21, 1937
- 0182. Box 1/Folder a4. Report on the Work of the Prisoners' Relief Department, by Rose Baron. 10 pages., 15 (Reel 1)
  Undated.
- 0192. Box 1/Folder a4. Report on the Labor Defender, by Sasha Small. 10 pages., 16 (Reel 1)
- 0202. Box 1/Folder a4. Report on Organizational Problems. By Sasha Small. 10 pages., 17 (Reel 1)
  Undated
- 0212. Box 1/Folder a5. Minutes and Reports., 1939; 18 (Reel 1)
- 0213. Box 1/Folder a5. Program for Round Table Discussions at the International Labor Defense National Conference To Be Held July 8-9, 1939. 5 pages., 19 (Reel 1)
  Topics Included: Prison conditions in America today and problem of aid to labor prisoners; legislation as it affects civil rights; the present situation in Puerto Rico; international aid to victims of Nazi and Fascist oppression - the problem of political refugees; problems of the foreign-born; anti-lynching legislation and defense of rights of Negro people; Fascist organizations at work in America today; civil rights in America today.
- 0218. Box 1/Folder a5. Proceedings and Report of the International Labor Department National Conference. 24 pages., 1939; 20 (Reel 1)
  July 8-9, 1939
- 0242. Box 1/Folder a5. Report of Legislative Activity of the International Labor Defense of Southern California, by Beulah Learned. 4 pages., 21 (Reel 1)
- 0246. Box 1/Folder a6. Minutes and Reports., 1943; 22 (Reel 1)
- 0247. Box 1/Folder a6. Report of Anna Damon, National Secretary, to the International Labor Defense National Conference. 18 pages., 1943; 23 (Reel 1)
  June 12, 1943. Topics Included: Legislative work; prisoners' relief; finances and organization.
- 0265. Box 1/Folder a6. Minutes of the International Labor Defense National Conference. 5 pages., 1943; 24 (Reel 1)
  June 12, 1943.
- 0270. Box 1/Folder a6. Report of Anna Damon, National Secretary, to the International Labor Defense National Conference. 7 pages., 1943; 25 (Reel 1)
- 0277. Box 1/Folder a6. List of Participants in the International Labor Defense National Conference. June 12, 1943. 4 pages., 26 (Reel 1)
- 0281. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes., 1939-1941; 27 (Reel 1)
- 0282. Box 1/Folder a7. Correspondence regarding meetings. 29 pages., 1939-1941; 28 (Reel 1)
- 0311. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 8 pages., 1939; 29 (Reel 1)
  November 4, 1939. Topics Included: Prison conditions; refugees; cases; organization; officers' recommendations.
- 0319. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 7 pages., 1939; 30 (Reel 1)
  November 28, 1939. Topics Included: Dies Committee; cases; peonage committees; membership; prisoners' relief; report on the budget for 1940.
- 0326. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 5 pages., 1939; 31 (Reel 1)
  December 21, 1939. Topics Included: Dies Committee; Washington Bureau and legislative work; organization; Marysville, California case; Tom Mooney; prisoners' aid; New York legislative conference; membership.
- 0331. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 8 pages., 1940; 32 (Reel 1)
  January 26, 1940. Topics Included: New York cases; Chicago, Illinois cases; California cases; Detroit, Michigan cases; membership; publications; Tom Mooney; New York state legislation; Washington Bureau and legislation; membership drive; prisoners' aid; Dies Committee - 1940 war-preparation role.
- 0339. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 3 pages., 1940; 33 (Reel 1)
  February 23, 1940. Topics Included: American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born committee conference; research fund; Detroit, Michigan cases; John Longo case; financial report; peonage cases; Earl Browder case.
- 0342. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 4 pages., 1940; 34 (Reel 1)
  April 12, 1940. Topics Included: John L. Spivak case; picketers of French Embassy case; membership drive; summer milk drive; [John] Longo case; peonage cases; Imperial Valley, California cases; Dies Committee; organization; J.B. McNamara; National Negro Congress; research fund.
- 0346. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 2 pages., 1940; 35 (Reel 1)
  November 15, 1940. Topics Included: Organization; Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania petition cases; Oklahoma cases.
- 0348. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 3 pages., 1940; 36 (Reel 1)
  December 11, 1940. Topics Included: Organization; Oklahoma cases; Christmas drive; legislative program.
- 0351. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 4 pages., 1941; 37 (Reel 1)
  January 17, 1941. Topics Included: Oklahoma cases; American Peace Mobilization; American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born; prisoners' relief; legislation; National Conference plans; budget for 1941.
- 0355. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 2 pages., 1941; 38 (Reel 1)
  February 14, 1941. Topics Included: Oklahoma cases; legislation; organization; National Conference plans.
- 0357. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 4 pages., 1941; 39 (Reel 1)
  March 7, 1941. Topics Included: J.B. McNamara; Oklahoma cases; American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born; Harry Bridges case; political prosecutions; National Conference plans.
- 0361. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 1 page., 1941; 40 (Reel 1)
  March 28, 1941. Topics Included: Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania cases; National Conference plans.
- 0362. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 2 pages., 1941; 41 (Reel 1)
  April 6, 1941. Topics Included: National Conference plans; National Office staff.
- 0364. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 4 pages., 1941; 42 (Reel 1)
  May 9, 1941. Topics Included: Oklahoma cases; membership drive; Harry Bridges case; milk drive; dismissal of Max Yergan from faculty of CCNY (?); lynching and increased discrimination against the Negro people; organizational questions.
- 0368. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 1 page., 1941; 43 (Reel 1)
  May 17, 1941. Topics Included: Marcantonio anti-discrimination bill; financial problems; Oklahoma cases.
- 0369. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 3 pages., 1941; 44 (Reel 1)
  June 20, 1941. Topics Included: Anti-peonage campaign; organizational matters; summer milk fund drive; Josephine Truslow Adams case; Oklahoma cases.
- 0372. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 3 pages., 1941; 45 (Reel 1)
  August 17, 1941. Topics Included: Violence and terror against the Negro people; Oklahoma cases; Dies Committee; President's Committee on Fair Employment Practices; Puerto Rican cases; elections; organization.
- 0375. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 11 pages., 1941; 46 (Reel 1)
  September 26, 1941. Topics Included: Oklahoma cases; Reginald Thomas case; Georgia peonage cases; Earl Browder case; membership drive; Christmas drive; organizational matters; Festus L. Coleman case; Herbert Newton case; Elmer Hanoff case; Sam Darcy case; Richmond, Indiana case; peonage cases; civil rights survey.
- 0386. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of Resident Board Meeting. 3 pages., 1941; 47 (Reel 1)
  October 17, 1941. Topics Included: Oklahoma cases; Christmas drive; membership drive; organizational matters; Reginald Thomas case.
- 0389. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 4 pages., 1941; 48 (Reel 1)
  November 21, 1941. Topics Included: Oklahoma cases; Reginald Thomas case; Earl Browder case; Christmas drive; 1942 budget; organizational matters; plans for National Committee meeting.
- 0393. Box 1/Folder a7. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 3 pages., 1941; 49 (Reel 1)
  December 19, 1941. Topics Included: Oklahoma cases; art sale; Christmas drive; Schneiderman case; statement by International Labor Defense officers to President Franklin D. Roosevelt.
- 0396. Box 1/Folder a7a. Minutes., 1842-1943; 50 (Reel 1)
- 0397. Box 1/Folder a7a. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 5 pages., 1942; 51 (Reel 1)
  June 1, 1942. Topics Included: Earl Browder case; New York City legislation; Harry Bridges case; American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born; the Rapp-Coudert Committee; Oklahoma cases; open letter to Francis Biddle; summer milk drive; communications; organization; Puerto Rican cases.
- 0402. Box 1/Folder a7a. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 5 pages., 1942; 52 (Reel 1)
  September 14, 1942. Topics Included: Puerto Rican cases; Harry Bridges case; Alexandria, Louisiana cases; David Williams case; Alphonso Wilson case; New York Communist party case; relief drives; organization; Oklahoma cases.
- 0407. Box 1/Folder a7a. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 3 pages., 1942; 53 (Reel 1)
  October 19, 1942. Topics Included: Oklahoma cases; Mississippi lynchings; David Williams case; New York Communist party case; membership drive; organizational matters.
- 0410. Box 1/Folder a7a. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 4 pages., 1942; 54 (Reel 1)
  November 30, 1942. Topics Included: Fair Employment Practices Commission; poll tax campaign; Oklahoma cases; National Emergency Committee to Stop Lynching; Jack Crane case; American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born; membership committee; organizational matters.
- 0414. Box 1/Folder a7a. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 9 pages., 1943; 55 (Reel 1)
  December 29, 1943. Topics Included: Organization and finance; Raissa Browder case; John Longo Case; Fair Employment Practices Commission; soldier vote and anti-poll tax bill.
- 0423. Box 1/Folder a7a. Report of Anna Damon, National Secretary, to the International Labor Defense National Conference. 7 pages., 1943; 56 (Reel 1)
- 0430. Box 1/Folder a8. Minutes. Anna Damon - Peerless Leader and Organizer. 2 pages., 1944; 57 (Reel 1)
  July 5, 1944. Topics Included: Statement adopted by the National Resident Board following her death.
- 0432. Box 1/Folder a9. Minutes of National Resident Board Meeting. 5 pages., 1945; 58 (Reel 1)
  February 23, 1945. Topics Included: New York state legislation; Mrs. Recy Taylor case; finances; organization; national service legislation; permanent Fair Employment Practices Commission legislation; anti-poll tax bill.
- 0437. Box 1/Folder a10. Financial Reports. 2 pages., 1930-1931; 59 (Reel 1)
  1930 [1931]
- 0439. Box 1/Folder a11. Financial Reports (May Labor Defender). 2 pages., 1932-1933; 60 (Reel 1)
  1932 [1933]
- 0441. Box 1/Folder a12. Financial Reports (July Labor Defender). 2 pages., 1934; 61 (Reel 1)
- 0443. Box 1/Folder a13. Financial Reports (April Labor Defender). 2 pages., 1935; 62 (Reel 1)
- 0445. Box 1/Folder a14. Financial Reports. (June Labor Defender). 2 pages., 1936; 63 (Reel 1)
- 0447. Box 1/Folder a15. Financial Reports. 8 pages., 1936-1937; 64 (Reel 1)
  1937 [1936-1937]
- 0455. Box 1/Folder a16. Financial Reports. 3 pages., 1941; 65 (Reel 1)
- 0458. Box 1/Folder a17. Financial Reports. 4 pages., 1943; 66 (Reel 1)
- 0462. Box 1/Folder a18. Financial Reports. 14 pages., 1944; 67 (Reel 1)
- 0476. Box 1/Folder a19. Financial Reports. 18 pages., 1945; 68 (Reel 1)
- 0484. Box 1/Folder b1. Publication: Equal Justice (Sasha Small; New York). 49 pages., 1938; 69 (Reel 1)
- 0543. Box 1/Folder b2. Publication: Equal Justice (Sasha Small; New York). 45 pages., 1939; 70 (Reel 1)
- 0588. Box 1/Folder b3. Publication: Equal Justice (Sasha Small; New York). 21 pages., 1940; 71 (Reel 1)
- 0609. Box 1/Folder b4. Publication: Equal Justice (Sasha Small; New York). 11 pages., 1941; 72 (Reel 1)
- 0620. Box 1/Folder b5. Publication: Equal Justice (Sasha Small; New York). 19 pages., 1942; 73 (Reel 1)
- 0639. Box 1/Folder b6. Publication: Labor Defender (William L. Patterson, Joseph North, Sasha Small, Louis Colman, Chester A. Arthur, Jr.; New York). 258 pages., 1933- 1934; 74 (Reel 1)
  1933-1934 (scattered issues)
- 0897. Box 1/Folder b7. Publication: Labor Defender (William L. Patterson, Joseph North, Sasha Small, Louis Colman, Chester A. Arthur, Jr.; New York). 103 pages., 1936- 1937; 75 (Reel 1)
  1936-1937 (scattered issues)
- 0980. Box 1/Folder b8. Publication: Legislative Information Service (Vito Marcantonio, Anna Damon, Louis Colman; New York). 16 pages., 1942; 76 (Reel 1)
- 0001. Box 1/Folder b9. Publications: Legislative and Information Service (Vito Marcantonio, Anna Damon, Louis Colman; New York). 22 pages., 1943; 1 (Reel 2)
- 0023. Box 1/Folder b10. Publications: Legislative and Information Service (Vito Marcantonio, Anna Damon, Louis Colman; New York). Poll Tax Filibuster Bulletins. 9 pages., 1943-1944; 2 (Reel 2)
- 0032. Box 1/Folder b11. Publications: Legislative and Information Service (Vito Marcantonio, Anna Damon, Louis Colman; New York). 105 pages., 1944; 3 (Reel 2)
- 0137. Box 1/Folder b12. Publications: Legislative and Information Service (Vito Marcantonio, Anna Damon, Louis Colman; New York). 65 pages., 1945; 4 (Reel 2)
- 0202. Box 1/Folder b13. Publications: Legislative and Information Service (Vito Marcantonio, Anna Damon, Louis Colman; New York). 8 pages., 1946; 5 (Reel 2)
- 0210. Box 1/Folder b14. Publication: Legislative Service (Vito Marcantonio; New York). 68 pages., 1946; 6 (Reel 2)
- 0278. Box 2/Folder b15. Publication: Legislative Service. 25 pages., 1946; 7 (Reel 2)
- 0303. Box 2/Folder b16. Publication: Hunger Fighter (Unemployed Council of Greater New York, Relief Workers' League of Greater New York; New York). 40 pages., 1932; 8 (Reel 2)
- 0343. Box 2/Folder b17. Publication: Hunger Fighter (Unemployed Council of Greater New York, Relief Workers' League of Greater New York; New York). 142 pages., 1933; 9 (Reel 2)
- 0485. Box 2/Folder b18. Publication: Hunger Fighter (Unemployed Council of Greater New York, Relief Workers' League of Greater New York; New York). 24 pages., 1934; 10 (Reel 2)
- 0509. Box 2/Folder b18a. Publication: International Labor Defense News (Vito Marcantonio, Anna Damon, Louis Colman, Sasha Small; New York). 96 pages., 1941- 1943; 11 (Reel 2)
- 0605. Box 2/Folder b19. Publication: International Labor Defense News (Vito Marcantonio, Anna Damon, Louis Colman, Sasha Small; New York). 100 pages., 1944; 12 (Reel 2)
- 0705. Box 2/Folder c1. Scottsboro case. Attorneys, etcetera. 66 pages., 1931; 13 (Reel 2)
- 0720. Box 2/Folder c1. Scottsboro case. Statement of Facts in the Scottsboro Case as Investigated by George Chamlee. 2 pages., 14 (Reel 2)
- 0722. Box 2/Folder c1. Scottsboro case. Statement of Facts in the Scottsboro Case. 7 pages., 1931; 15 (Reel 2)
  April 21, 1931.
- 0729. Box 2/Folder c1. Scottsboro case. Statement by George Chamblee. 2 pages., 1931; 16 (Reel 2)
  April 22, 1931.
- 0731. Box 2/Folder c1. Scottsboro case. Report on Steve Roddy [former Scottsboro Case attorney]. 2 pages., 1931; 17 (Reel 2)
  April 26, 1931.
- 0768. Box 2/Folder c1. Scottsboro case. Names of Witnesses, Families, etcetera. 2 pages., 18 (Reel 2)
- 0771. Box 2/Folder c2. Scottsboro case. Attorneys, etcetera. 44 pages., 1932; 19 (Reel 2)
- 0775. Box 2/Folder c2. [Scottsboro case. Powell v. Alabama. Alabama Supreme Court.] Dissenting Opinion by Chief Justice John C. Anderson. 6 pages., 1932; 20 (Reel 2)
  March 1932.
- 0815. Box 2/Folder c3. Scottsboro case. Attorneys, etcetera. 29 pages., 1933; 21 (Reel 2)
- 0824. Box 2/Folder c3. Scottsboro case. Statement of George Chamlee regarding Testimony of Ruby Bates Recanting her Previous Testimony. 2 pages., 1933; 22 (Reel 2)
  May 1933
- 0828. Box 2/Folder c3. Scottsboro case. Statements of Osmund Fraenkel regarding Cases before the Alabama Supreme Court. 8 pages., 1934; 23 (Reel 2)
  July 1934
- 0844. Box 2/Folder c4. Scottsboro case. Retention of Samuel Leibowitz. 11 pages., 1933; 24 (Reel 2)
  January 1933
- 0855. Box 2/Folder c5. Scottsboro case. Lynch Affidavits. 69 pages., 1933; 25 (Reel 2)
  August 1933
- 0856. Box 2/Folder c5. Scottsboro case. Alabama v. Patterson. Circuit Court of Morgan County, Alabama. Depositions of Victor Ellwood. 36 pages., 1933; 26 (Reel 2)
- 0892. Box 2/Folder c5. Scottsboro case. Alabama vs. Patterson. Circuit Court of Morgan County, Alabama. Deposition of David Schriftman. 5 pages., 1933; 27 (Reel 2)
- 0897. Box 2/Folder c5. Scottsboro case. Alabama v. Patterson. Circuit Court of Morgan County, Alabama. Deposition of John Williams. 5 pages., 1933; 28 (Reel 2)
- 0902. Box 2/Folder c5. Scottsboro case. Alabama v. Patterson, et al. Circuit Court of Morgan County, Alabama. Deposition of Victor Ellwood. 11 pages., 1933; 29 (Reel 2)